Guide to the Astronomical Observatory, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Astronomical Observatory, Yale University, records
1874-1890
RU 416
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The records consist of correspondence, letter books, financial papers, reports, and recommendations documenting the period of planning and construction of the Astronomical Observatory, also known as the Yale University Observatory. Notable contributors to the records include Leonard Waldo, astronomer in charge of the Horological Bureau of the Observatory; Robert Brown, secretary of the Board of Managers; and Hubert A. Newton, director of the observatory.
Yale University. Department of Astronomy
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by record type.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, letter books, financial papers, reports, and recommendations documenting the period of planning and construction of the Astronomical Observatory, also known as the Yale University Observatory. Notable contributors to the records include Leonard Waldo, astronomer in charge of the Horological Bureau of the Observatory; Robert Brown, secretary of the Board of Managers; and Hubert A. Newton, director of the observatory.
Astronomical observatories; College buildings; Observatories; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Brown, Robert, 1836-1911; Newton, H. A. (Hubert Anson), 1830-1896; Waldo, Leonard, 1853-; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Department of Astronomy; Yale University. Observatory
- Records, 1874-1890; Accession 1932-A-001
  - Letterbook, 1879-1890 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Correspondence
    - A, 1880-1883 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - B, 1879-1884 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Brown, R., 1882-1890 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - C, 1874-1887 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - D, 1882-1890 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - E, 1881-1883 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - F, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - H, 1881-1890 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - I-K, 1883-1887 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - L, 1884-1887 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - M-N, 1880-1884 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Newton, H. A., 1875-1887 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - O-P-Q, 1884-1891 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - R, 1879-1888 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - S, 1883-1886 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - T, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - W, 1881-1890 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Waldo, L., 1879-1884 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - X-Y-Z, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Special documents, 1871-1884 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Financial papers, 1881-1887 (Box 3, Folder 24 - 25)
  - Observatory records, 1872-1889 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Astronomical work & instruments, 1880-1892 (Box 3, Folder 27 - 28)
  - Board of Managers: Recommendations, records of the Observatory, 1880s (Box 3, Folder 29)